Wait, your dad's been dead for years?
Yeah. I heard her loud and clear.
She said it when she was on
the phone with his mom.
And you're sure she was
talking about your dad?!
Senpai...
You're sure you're not taking
something out of context?!
She didn't say my dad's name...
But she was talking to his mom.
Who else would they be talking about?
And the way she said "it doesn't matter"...
like she really doesn't
care about him anymore.
Like she doesn't want anything to do with him at all.
And why didn't she tell me he's gone?
I love my dad.
Hearing how much she hates him just,
like, broke me.
I was too scared to even say anything.
Destiny
Aria-chan...
Ririsa...
Mayura-sama taught me this might help you feel better.
Nono-pi...
GLANCE
Mikarin!
You coming?
I'll pass!
But...
My heart's with you.
Thanks, everyone.
C'mon, we're doing detail work today, right?
Up and at 'em, girls!
Wait, but...
We can't abandon our cosplays now!
Not when I'm finding out how fun this is!
Besides, the most important thing
is showing him how much I love him.
That's why people visit their family's graves, right?
I think it depends on the person...
Plus, if Okumura died on us...
Wait, what?!
I bet Liliel would be waiting for
him at the gates of heaven.
My dad loved his manga.
I'm sure Melia is there waiting to open the gates for him.
C'mon, Ririsa, let's get started!
O-okay!
Wait, let me try on the skirt first.
Okay, I'll step out!
Aria's tougher than I thought.
Maybe she's pretending she's okay,
but the fact that she can
just shows how tough she is.
But, something just doesn't feel right...
The same something
I felt when started talking about VB.
Valykrie Battle
I'm not sure what, though...
But, something's telling me that Kisaki-sensei isn't dead.
I'm gonna have to do some research.
Wow, what a feast!
What inspired you today?
I was lost in thought and ended
up making way too much.
Aww, thanks, Aria.
I'm gonna be swamped with orders for
Obon season starting tomorrow.
Hey, Mom?
What? I'm right here.
Do you think marrying Dad was a mistake?
Huh? Where's this coming from?
Do you think you should've
married a rich guy instead?
I don't mind not having money,
so long as I can live a happy life.
Wait, do you think I divorced
him because he had no money?!
I divorced him because he lost sight of his dream.
Really?
I'm partially to blame, too.
I turned his passion into a tool to bring
in money and support our family.
We were unhappy, and I knew if I stayed with him,
I'd only make him less happy.
So I did what was best for both of us.
So you don't hate him?
Your father was a good man.
He just wasn't the right
person for me or our family.
Look, Aria.
Life is a long series of one event after another.
You can look back on them and call those
events successes or mistakes if you want.
But you can't change how you
felt at the time they happened.
You don't have to say you hate someone
just because you broke up with them.
I was happy then, and happy now.
Back then, I loved him with my whole heart.
That fact will never change.
Mom...
Life is about finding happiness.
Don't waste it on a man
who won't give that to you.
Okay.
Morning, babes!
Aria-chan!
I'm glad you're doing better!
I'm like, better than better.
Wait, what's with the tension over there?
Senpai's been like this all day.
I think he's trying to find something online?
What'd you find, Senpai?!
I felt like something was off yesterday...
So I started doing some research on Aria's dad.
Huh?!
Check this out.
I found a bonus manga that wasn't
published in any of the VB volumes.
Whoa, I can't believe you dug this up!
Look at this!
"Our esteemed master" is what
Takamatsu-sensei's assistants all called him!
No one else online seems to have noticed,
but I'm pretty sure of it...
Kisaki-sensei was an apprentice to the author
of the Ashford Chronicles, Takamatsu-sensei!
The guy who created Liliel? I had no idea...
Dad never talked about his work at home.
Even if he did,
I was too little to remember.
Valykrie Battle
That's probably why people said
VB was similar to Ashford Chronicles.
And probably why the Liliel
anime felt so familiar to me, too.
So, what does this all mean?
It'll all make sense when you
see this next thing I discovered!
Look at this right here!
That's Melia!
No, look closer!
At her ear?
Every manga artist has their own way of drawing ears.
Even if their art style changes,
their ear design usually stays the same.
You can always tell by the ears.
Senpai, why are you bringing this up?
Ririsa, look closely.
Do you recognize that ear?
Wait, no way...
Okay, why are you freaking out?!
Aria...
Your dad isn't dead.
...what?
F-for real?! How do you know?!
And hold up...
Why is Okumura crying?!
If Kisaki-sensei had died years ago,
then none of this would be here...
I think after his divorce,
he couldn't get a new series picked up...
...so, because his art style was similar,
he found work with his old master.
Wait...
He changed his pen name and kept making manga.
A spinoff of his former master's manga.
Aria...
I think your dad...
...wrote our bible,
Liliel: Side Story!
How's it going, Sensei?
Sensei?
Kisaki-san!
Sorry, I thought you'd be out today.
Classical music?
So that's what you're always
listening to on your headphones.
Osamu Tezuka-sensei said to listen
to the highest form of music, so...
I think that advice was just for newbies getting started...
I mean, I did it too, way back when.
Also, you got some fan mail.
Thanks, but could you pass that
along to Takamatsu-sensei?
You don't want to read it?
They're all from fans of Side Story.
Liliel belongs to my esteemed...
Er, Takamatsu-sensei.
I just write the spinoff.
The only fan mail I ever got
was one letter ten years ago.
C'mon, don't let it go to waste.
I'm still waiting for my big debut,
and if I knew I had a single fan,
I'd be over the moon.
And you're sure about that?
Huh?
If a million readers raked your work over the coals,
would you be happy to have a single fan?
Mita-kun, the reason you want to publish in Jump...
..is so you can have a million
readers fall in love with your work, right?
True...
All these failed pitches might be getting to me.
Maybe I wouldn't be happy if that happened.
No, you'd be over the moon.
You tricked me!
I was happy to have a fan, too.
I felt that, even if those million readers hated it,
if one person liked it,
then it was worth making.
You still have it?
I wish I hadn't sent him such a disappointing response.
I was so worried he would
suffer for liking my manga.
Everyone was saying it was a garbage rip-off.
They'd even attack people
who said they read the manga.
I didn't want him to get
bullied for liking my manga.
It was all too possible.
But he loved my manga.
I wish I'd told him how much it meant to me.
At the time, I truly believed
I deserved to disappear into obscurity.
Working on the final chapters
of a canceled manga
is a hell I hope you never
have to experience, Mita-kun.
It's already tough enough putting
out one chapter a week.
But now, you have to write a thrilling climax for
a manga no one really cares about anymore.
It's like being a comedian who has to finish his set,
even though no one's laughing.
You're sweaty and nauseous,
but you have to stay up on stage.
Soon enough, you start believing them,
but you can't stop making the trash they hate.
You start to hate your work, to hate yourself.
Every day, every minute that ticks closer
to your deadline feels like an eternity.
There were so many times I thought about
turning in something rushed and half-assed.
But still, there was a boy out there
who thought my manga was good.
Though my work would be read by a million readers,
I wrote those hundred pages for one boy.
Even now, people only remember the
series for being forgettable garbage.
But because I didn't throw in the towel,
now I get to keep working as a manga artist.
All thanks to one fan.
Oh, actually, two fans.
My daughter loved my manga.
I was so obsessed with work back then,
I forgot to give her the love
and attention she deserved...
He was the same age as my daughter.
Manga Club
I hope both of them still love manga now.
Liliel!
Huh?
Iconic Senpai.
Hello.
Hey, babe!
Okumura?
I went back to the anime to
check stuff and got distracted.
Did you ask your mom about that phone call, Aria?
Yeah. I asked her about it yesterday, and, uh...
You mean that call with your grandmother?
She called about one of his
relatives that passed a while back.
What?! Why was she calling you about that?!
God, it's so stupid.
I lent him 100K yen a long time ago.
We hit it off at a family funeral,
and I was happy to help.
You hit it off at a funeral?
Anyway, he told me he couldn't pay me back,
so I stopped talking to him.
He died five years ago.
Grandma apparently found out about the
debt and wants to make sure I'm paid back.
But, I honestly don't care about him or the cash,
so I told her to forget it.
Were you just curious, or...
N-no.... never mind.
So Okumura was totally right,
I was taking it out context... My bad.
It's okay!
No, that's good. That all but confirms it.
Kisaki-sensei has to be the author of Liliel: Side Story!
I still don't fully believe it...
But, you're the biggest Liliel Otaku in the world,
so I think we have to.
Ever since you mentioned it,
I've noticed how similar the art and story is.
This is crazy...
The artist who created the first
manga I fell in love with...
...has been bringing us new
Liliel content for the past ten years.
Senpai...
But, I shouldn't get emotional about
this until we know for sure.
Okay, but if that's true,
then if our Liliel cosplays stand out...
...then there's a good chance
Kisaki-sensei will hear about them!
Now I'm super pumped to get this done.
Let's finish our costumes, Ririsa!
Yeah! With summer break just around the corner,
we'll have tons of time!
I'll help, too!
Don't forget about your homework, though.
Aria-chan, Aria-chan!
Wait, that's so good!
What's good?
Nothing you need to know.
hehehe
You guys should know that
Comiket's got its upsides and downsides.
Comiket's absolutely ginormous.
They've got set locations and structured
lines to corral those thousands of attendees.
Photo time is extremely limited,
and tons of famous cosplayers will be there, too.
That includes all four of the Heavenly Queens.
B-but hey, Liliel and Nono-pi are ranked
fifth and fourth on the Rising Stars list!
First through third will be there, too.
Mr. Camera said he'd announced
who they were before Comiket.
And our photos will be drowned out by
the ocean of Comiket pics posted online.
It's actually harder to go viral from
Comiket than other events.
Especially, Summer Comiket.
It's practically haunted.
Haunted?
We should aim for Day 3,
since that's when cosplayers
will be selling their ROMs.
Nagomi might stay, but Erica and Yoki might not.
Okay! And this year's Comiket
is August 8th through 11th, so...
Oh, I can't. My mom and I leave on the
10th to visit our family grave for Obon.
You're so normal!
That's so nice of you!
You two know you're going to hell, right?
All that's left, then, is to make your announcement.
Most people decide who they want
to see the day before they go,
so posting about it is critical.
I-I posted about it,
but I didn't get as many shares as Nagomi-san...
Okay, fine.
I guess I can make some kind of announcement.
You're the best, Mikari-chan!
If Mikarin makes a post on her socials, we're golden...
Please.
If our competition is posting online,
I'm not about to stoop to their level.
I'm gonna be at Comiket on Day 1
with a Liliel Defense Squadron group!
Whoa, hold on, you serious?!
You're gonna be cosplaying?!
Yeah! I even made my costume!
You announced it on TV...
Well? Didn't I do good?
Sensei, you're not gonna believe this!
Mikarin is going to Comiket in a Liliel cosplay!
You lucky dog, you!
Who?
Seriously?
You know that cute Liliel cosplayer that
went around social media recently?
Yeah, I heard something about that.
She's gonna be cosplaying with her!
We've gotta go see them in person!
No, I'll pass. It'll be too hot and crowded.
What, and give up the opportunity to
see your characters cosplayed?!
You've gotta want to see them in person!
Cosplayers are getting
crazy good these days, too!
I'd want to if it were my own series.
Not this again.
They're doing the Airborne Defense Squadron!
That's Side Story!
And Ariel isn't in the original! She's your character!
Don't you want to see Ariel in person?
Did I upset him?
Oh! I know this song, Sensei!
It's the one where the violin and G?
Johann Sebastian Bach,
Orchestral Suite No. 3 in D Major,
second movement, Air on the G String.
Or, "Aria."
It's my favorite piece of music in the entire world.
Mita-kun, let me think it over.
All right!
The contours, the reflectivity,
the scaling, the overall balance...
It's perfect!
We passed Okumura's final check!
So that means...
Ariel is done!
Thanks, everyone!
Took you guys long enough.
Valykrie Battle
Just you wait, Kisaki-sensei.
You don't need to protect me.
I'll tell everyone how much I love your
series a thousand times if I have to.
Because that's what otaku do!
I always get so excited the morning of.
Same!
Ririsa-chan!
Morning, babes!
Morning!
Senpai!
Okay, we're all here.
We should get to Kokusai-Tenjijo station before 8.
It's nice getting to relax.
Usually, I'm on the first train here.
Wait, at like 4 AM?!
You guys are nuts.
Everyone feeling good?
It's gonna get hot today.
I had a hard time getting to sleep 'cause I was so excited.
I'm full of energy!
Remember everything today, Ririsa?
I-I've got everything!
Hey, you made that mistake once,
now you'll never make it again!
I slept well, ate breakfast,
remembered everything, and am ready to go!
I've got zero anxiety this morning!
You just jinxed it!
They must all be cosplayers. They've all got bags.
Look at that guy and his harem. Lucky bastard.
Harem? You've got it wrong.
Those are the eyes of a man
who only gets aroused by 2D girls!
Forgive me, comrade.
Comrade.
Hello, comrades.
Let's go! It's time...
...for Comiket!
Time for Summer Comiket!